{"id": 1, "inst/question": "A brownie recipe is asking for 350 grams of sugar, and a pound cake recipe requires 270 more grams of sugar than a brownie recipe. How many grams of sugar are needed for the pound cake?", "inst/gold_answer": 620.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 2, "inst/question": "The size of a compressed file is 1.74 MiB, while the size of the original uncompressed file is 5.5 times greater. What is the size of the uncompressed file, in MiB?", "inst/gold_answer": 9.57, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 3, "inst/question": "Margo is 5 years old and Ivan is 34 years older than Margo. How old is Ivan?", "inst/gold_answer": 39.0, "plan": "Method: System of linear equations"}
{"id": 4, "inst/question": "Alice runs 1.9 times faster than Bob, who runs at 4.7 mph. How fast does Alice run, in mph?", "inst/gold_answer": 8.93, "plan": "Method: System of linear equations"}
{"id": 5, "inst/question": "Tao\u2019s first car was 3 times cheaper than his second car, and he bought his second car for 7899 dollars. How much was Tao\u2019s first car?", "inst/gold_answer": 2633.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 6, "inst/question": "The profit of ACME Corporation in the second quarter was 8.84 billion dollars, which was 1.3 times greater than the profit in the first quarter. What was ACME\u2019s profit in the first quarter?", "inst/gold_answer": 6.8, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 7, "inst/question": "The width of a rectangle is 125 meters shorter than the length. Find the length if the width is 205 meters.", "inst/gold_answer": 330.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 8, "inst/question": "The payout for playing a single number on a roulette table is 35 times greater than the bet. Cindy receives the payout of $3850. How much was Cindy\u2019s bet?", "inst/gold_answer": 110.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 9, "inst/question": "A history textbook costs $90, which is five times cheaper than an anatomy textbook. Find the price of the anatomy text.", "inst/gold_answer": 450.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 10, "inst/question": "According to NASA, the global land-ocean temperature index (average surface temperature of Earth) in 2016 is 1.26 \u25e6C greater than it was in 1920. Find the average temperature in 1920 if it was 0.99 \u25e6C in 2016.", "inst/gold_answer": -0.27, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 11, "inst/question": "Damian\u2019s age is one year less than twice the Colin\u2019s age. How old is Colin, if Damian is 17 years old?", "inst/gold_answer": 9.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 12, "inst/question": "Bob says to Alice: if you give me 3 apples and then take half of my apples away, then I will be left with 13 apples. How many apples do I have now?", "inst/gold_answer": 23.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 13, "inst/question": "Alice works two jobs. Her full-time job pays four times more than her part-time job, and together they pay 3800 dollars per month. Find how much her full-time job pays per month.", "inst/gold_answer": 3040.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 14, "inst/question": "Rita bought rice and truffles a grocery store, and she paid $67.5 more for truffles than she paid for the rice. Find the price of rice if the total bill was $72.", "inst/gold_answer": 2.25, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 15, "inst/question": "Alice, Bob, and Charlie stand to inherit 12000 dollars, and the will stipulates that the inheritance is to be split in such a way that Bob gets two times more money than Alice, while Charlie should get 1600 dollars less than Alice. Find the inheritance amount for Alice.", "inst/gold_answer": 3400.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 16, "inst/question": "Katy invested some money into bonds, and the amount of interest earned after one year was 25 times smaller than the original investment. Find the interest if the total amount in her account is $546.", "inst/gold_answer": 21.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 17, "inst/question": "An \u00e9clair has five times as many calories as a latte, and together they have 264 calories. Find how many calories an \u00e9clair has.", "inst/gold_answer": 220.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 18, "inst/question": "The width of a rectangular parking lot is 40 feet shorter than its length. Find the width of the lot if its perimeter is 640 feet.", "inst/gold_answer": 140.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 19, "inst/question": "Consider an astronomical triangle with sides a, b, and c, such that the length of the side b is 3 light-years longer the length of a, and the length of c is 6 times shorter than the length of a. Find the length of side a if the perimeter of the triangle is 55 light-years.", "inst/gold_answer": 24.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 20, "inst/question": "A monthly pass for light rail is 1.2 times cheaper than the a bundle with 20 day passes. Find the price of the monthly pass if the bundle costs $10 more than the monthly pass.", "inst/gold_answer": 50.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 21, "inst/question": "A bread recipe calls for a mix of bleached flour, whole wheat flour, and rye flour. The volume of whole wheat should be two times greater than the volume of bleached, and the volume of rye should be 1 cup less than the volume of bleached. Find the volume in cups for bleached flour if the recipe is asking for 15 cups of flour in total.", "inst/gold_answer": 4.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 22, "inst/question": "The number 21 is what percent of 70?", "inst/gold_answer": 30.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 23, "inst/question": "The number 330 is 120% of what number?", "inst/gold_answer": 275.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 24, "inst/question": "A department store puts up shirts on sale at 35% discount. Find the original price of a shirt before the discount if the new price is $26.", "inst/gold_answer": 40.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 26, "inst/question": "Suzy earned $208 in tips after 20% income tax. What was her pre-tax income?", "inst/gold_answer": 260.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 27, "inst/question": "A department store puts dresses up for sale at 30% discount. If the discounted price of a dress is $42, what was the original price before the discount?", "inst/gold_answer": 60.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 29, "inst/question": "Brent paid $5824 for a car, and this price included the 4% sales tax. How much did the car cost before the sales tax was applied?", "inst/gold_answer": 5600.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 30, "inst/question": "Roger paid $238 for a webcam during a 15%-off sale. Find the original price of the webcam.", "inst/gold_answer": 280.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 34, "inst/question": "Apu takes the express train from Springfield to Capital City, and a regular train on his way back from Capital City to Springfield. The express completes the trip in 4 hours 30 minutes, while the regular train covers the same distance in 6 hours. Find the speed of the express, in miles per hour, if the express runs 15 miles per hour faster.", "inst/gold_answer": 60.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 35, "inst/question": "Kay and July are opening the incoming mail together, with the goal of processing 400 envelopes. Find how many hours they need to complete the task if Kay can process 15 envelopes per hour, and July can process 35 envelopes per hour.", "inst/gold_answer": 8.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 36, "inst/question": "One morning Aristotle starts walking from Athens to Megara, and at the same time Socrates starts on a journey from Megara to Athens. Being younger, Aristotle is walking 1.8 times faster than Socrates. After a 5 hour journey, they meet somewhere in the middle of the way. Find the speed of Aristotle, in km per hour, if the total distance between Athens and Megara is 42 km.", "inst/gold_answer": 5.4, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 37, "inst/question": "The top speed of a bullet train is 210 km per hour. Find how many hours it takes to travel 168 km at top speed.", "inst/gold_answer": 0.8, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 40, "inst/question": "Jamie charges $80 per hour for her paralegal work. Find how many hours she has to work in order to earn $2000.", "inst/gold_answer": 25.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 42, "inst/question": "Alice paddled for 3 hours upstream and then for 2 hours downstream. When going downstream, her speed was 10 mph greater than her speed when going upstream. The total distance traveled was 30 miles. How fast did Alice travel upstream, in mph?", "inst/gold_answer": 2.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 43, "inst/question": "Ridwan can plant 4 trees per hour, and Sue can plant 5.5 trees per hour. Find how many hours they need to plant 285 trees, if they are working together.", "inst/gold_answer": 30.0, "plan": "Method: System of linear equations"}
{"id": 44, "inst/question": "A passenger and a freight train start toward each other at the same time from two points 300 miles apart. If the rate of the passenger train exceeds the rate of the freight train by 15 miles per hour, and they meet after 4 hours, what must the rate of the passenger be, in miles per hour?", "inst/gold_answer": 45.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 45, "inst/question": "Lab 1 can process blood samples 3 times faster than Lab 2. Working together, the two labs can process 84 samples over 7 days. Find the rate of work for Lab 1, in samples per day.", "inst/gold_answer": 9.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 46, "inst/question": "Two automobiles started at the same time from a point, but traveled in opposite directions. Their rates were 25 and 35 miles per hour respectively. After how many hours were they 180 miles apart?", "inst/gold_answer": 3.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 47, "inst/question": "Suzy pays $111 for an order of 4 black printer cartridges and 7 color cartridges. When supplies start running low, she goes back to the same store and pays $126 for an order of 3 black and 10 color cartridges. Find the price of one black cartridge.", "inst/gold_answer": 12.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 48, "inst/question": "A chemist receives an order for 10 liters of 48% isopropyl solution, that is, a solution consisting of 48 parts of isopropyl alcohol and 52 parts of water by volume. The stockroom only has some 15% solution and some 70% solution. How many liters of the 15% solution is needed in order to fulfill the order?", "inst/gold_answer": 4.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 49, "inst/question": "Charlie has in his coin jar a certain number of quarters and nickels. There are 77 coins in the jar, and together they are worth $6.05. Find how many quarters are in the jar.", "inst/gold_answer": 11.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 50, "inst/question": "A collection of dimes and quarters is worth $15.25. There are 103 coins in all. How many of dimes are there?", "inst/gold_answer": 70.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 51, "inst/question": "There were 429 people at a play. Admission was $1 each for adults and 75 cents each for children. The receipts were $372.50. How many children attended?", "inst/gold_answer": 226.0, "plan": "Method: System of linear equations"}
{"id": 52, "inst/question": "A total of $27000 is invested, part of it at 12% and the rest at 13%. The total interest after one year is $3385. How much was invested at 12%?", "inst/gold_answer": 12500.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 53, "inst/question": "A coin bank contains nickels and dimes. The number of dimes is 10 less than twice the number of nickels. The total value of all the coins is $2.75. Find the number of nicklels in the bank.", "inst/gold_answer": 15.0, "plan": "Method: System of linear equations"}
{"id": 54, "inst/question": "A total of $9000 is invested, part of it at 10% and the rest at 12%. The total interest after one year is $1030. How much was invested at 10%?", "inst/gold_answer": 2500.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 55, "inst/question": "At a coin-operated laundromat, using the washer 6 times and then the dryer 6 times costs $13.50, while using the washer 4 times and then the dryer 8 times costs $12. Find the cost of one wash.", "inst/gold_answer": 1.5, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 56, "inst/question": "A tea that is 20% jasmine is blended with a tea that is 15% jasmine. How many pounds of 20% jasmine tea are needed to make 5 lb of tea that is 18% jasmine?", "inst/gold_answer": 3.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 57, "inst/question": "A party with 3 adults and 2 children pays 45 dollars for their tickets at Acme Theater. Another party, with 4 adults and 4 children, pays 68 dollars. Find the price of one adult ticket.", "inst/gold_answer": 11.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 58, "inst/question": "Every Monday Helen shares coffee and donuts with the office where she works. One week Helen buys 4 cups of coffee and 6 donuts, and pays 18 dollars. The next week Helen buys 6 cups of coffee and 12 donuts, and pays 30 dollars. Find the price of one cup of coffee.", "inst/gold_answer": 3.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 59, "inst/question": "Ivan\u2019s math class has 1.2 times more students than Ivan\u2019s statistics class. Find how many people are enrolled in the statistics class has if the math class has 30 students.", "inst/gold_answer": 25.0, "plan": "Method: System of linear equations"}
{"id": 60, "inst/question": "Bart, Millhouse, and Martin Prince saved up 149 dollars for a collectible comic book. Find how much money Bart saved up if Bart contributed 3 times less than Millhouse, and Martin contributed 9 dollars more than Millhouse.", "inst/gold_answer": 20.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 61, "inst/question": "A quantity increased by 14% and is now 171. Find the quantity before the increase.", "inst/gold_answer": 150.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 62, "inst/question": "A quantity decreased from 140 to 133. Find the percent decrease.", "inst/gold_answer": 5.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 63, "inst/question": "John paid 24% income tax on the total income of $28,000. Find how much money John has made after tax.", "inst/gold_answer": 21280.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 64, "inst/question": "A contractor buys a residential property, renovates it, and then sells (flips) it with 25% markup. If the the sale price is $160, 000, find how much the contractor has paid for the property.", "inst/gold_answer": 128000.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 65, "inst/question": "Shannon\u2019s business serves 14 clients per day on average. Find the time needed to serve 518 clients, in days.", "inst/gold_answer": 37.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 67, "inst/question": "Jane\u2019s monthly car loan payment is one quarter of her monthly house loan payment. Find her monthly car loan payment rate, in dollars per month, if Jane pays 19200 dollars in total over the course of the year.", "inst/gold_answer": 320.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 74, "inst/question": "Javier owns 300 shares of stock in one company. On Tuesday, the stock price dropped $12 per share. What was the total effect on Javier\u2019s portfolio?", "inst/gold_answer": -3600.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 76, "inst/question": "Field trip All the 5th graders at Lincoln Elementary School will go on a field trip to the science museum. Counting all the children, teachers, and chaperones, there will be 147 people. Each bus holds 44 people. How many busses will be needed?", "inst/gold_answer": 4.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 79, "inst/question": "The MacIntyre family recycled newspapers for two months. The two months of newspapers weighed a total of 57 pounds. The second month, the newspapers weighed 28 pounds. How much did the newspapers weigh the first month?", "inst/gold_answer": 29.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 80, "inst/question": "Randell paid $28,675 for his new car. This was $875 less than the sticker price. What was the sticker price of the car?", "inst/gold_answer": 29550.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 81, "inst/question": "Avril rode her bike a total of 18 miles, from home to the library and then to the beach. The distance from Avril\u2019s house to the library is 7 miles. What is the distance from the library to the beach, in miles?", "inst/gold_answer": 11.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 82, "inst/question": "Eva\u2019s daughter is 15 years younger than her son. Eva\u2019s son is 22 years old. How old is her daughter?", "inst/gold_answer": 7.0, "plan": "Method: System of linear equations"}
{"id": 83, "inst/question": "For a family birthday dinner, Celeste bought a turkey that weighed 5 pounds less than the one she bought for Thanksgiving. The birthday turkey weighed 16 pounds. How much did the Thanksgiving turkey weigh, in pounds?", "inst/gold_answer": 21.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 84, "inst/question": "Connor\u2019s temperature was 0.7 degrees higher this morning than it had been last night. His temperature this morning was 101.2 degrees. What was his temperature last night?", "inst/gold_answer": 100.5, "plan": "Method: System of linear equations"}
{"id": 85, "inst/question": "Ron\u2019s paycheck this week was $17.43 less than his paycheck last week. His paycheck this week was $103.76. How much was Ron\u2019s paycheck last week?", "inst/gold_answer": 121.19, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 86, "inst/question": "Denae bought 6 pounds of grapes for $10.74. What was the cost of one pound of grapes?", "inst/gold_answer": 1.79, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 87, "inst/question": "Andreas bought a used car for $12,000. Because the car was 4-years old, its price was 3/4 of the original price, when the car was new. What was the original price of the car?", "inst/gold_answer": 16000.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 88, "inst/question": "Ramona bought 18 balloons for a party. She wants to make 3 equal bunches. How many balloons did she use in each bunch?", "inst/gold_answer": 6.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 89, "inst/question": "Serena paid $12.96 for a pack of 12 pairs of sport socks. What was the price of pair of sport socks?", "inst/gold_answer": 1.08, "plan": "Method: System of linear equations"}
{"id": 90, "inst/question": "John\u2019s SUV gets 18 miles per gallon (mpg). This is half as many mpg as his wife\u2019s hybrid car. How many miles per gallon does the hybrid car get?", "inst/gold_answer": 36.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 91, "inst/question": "Bea earned $11,700 commission for selling a house, calculated as 6/100 selling price. What was the selling price of the house?", "inst/gold_answer": 195000.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 96, "inst/question": "Philip got a ride with a friend from Denver to Las Vegas, a distance of 750 miles. If the trip took 10 hours, how fast was the friend driving, in miles per hour?", "inst/gold_answer": 75.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 97, "inst/question": "Tan weighs 146 pounds. Minh weighs 15 pounds more than Tan. How much does Minh weigh?", "inst/gold_answer": 161.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 98, "inst/question": "Elissa earned $152.84 this week, which was $21.65 more than she earned last week. How much did she earn last week?", "inst/gold_answer": 131.19, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 99, "inst/question": "Janet gets paid $24 per hour. She heard that this is 3/4 of what Adam is paid. How much is Adam paid per hour?", "inst/gold_answer": 32.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 100, "inst/question": "Two-thirds of the children in the fourth-grade class are girls. If there are 20 girls, what is the total number of children in the class?", "inst/gold_answer": 30.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 101, "inst/question": "Zachary has 25 country music CDs, which is one-fifth of his CD collection. How many CDs does Zachary have?", "inst/gold_answer": 125.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 102, "inst/question": "There are 16 girls in a school club. The number of girls is four more than twice the number of boys. Find the number of boys.", "inst/gold_answer": 6.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 103, "inst/question": "Huong is organizing paperback and hardback books for her club\u2019s used book sale. The number of paperbacks is 12 less than three times the number of hardbacks. Huong had 162 paperbacks. How many hardback books were there?", "inst/gold_answer": 58.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 104, "inst/question": "Philip pays $1,620 in rent every month. This amount is $120 more than twice what his brother Paul pays for rent. How much does Paul pay for rent?", "inst/gold_answer": 750.0, "plan": "Method: System of linear equations"}
{"id": 105, "inst/question": "Laurie has $46,000 invested in stocks and bonds. The amount invested in stocks is $8,000 less than three times the amount invested in bonds. How much does Laurie have invested in bonds?", "inst/gold_answer": 13500.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 106, "inst/question": "The sum of a number and eight is 12. Find the number.", "inst/gold_answer": 4.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 107, "inst/question": "The sum of three times a number and eight is 23. Find the number.", "inst/gold_answer": 5.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 108, "inst/question": "Three times the sum of a number and nine is 12. Find the number.", "inst/gold_answer": -5.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 109, "inst/question": "Patty paid $35 for a purse on sale for $10 off the original price. What was the original price of the purse?", "inst/gold_answer": 45.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 110, "inst/question": "Minh spent $6.25 on five sticker books to give his nephews. Find the cost of each sticker book.", "inst/gold_answer": 1.25, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 111, "inst/question": "Tom paid $1,166.40 for a new refrigerator, including $86.40 tax. What was the price of the refrigerator?", "inst/gold_answer": 1080.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 112, "inst/question": "Dezohn and his girlfriend enjoyed a nice dinner at a restaurant and his bill was $68.50. He wants to leave an 18% tip. If the tip will be 18% of the total bill, how much tip should he leave?", "inst/gold_answer": 12.33, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 113, "inst/question": "The label on Masao\u2019s breakfast cereal said that one serving of cereal provides 85 milligrams (mg) of potassium, which is 2% of the recommended daily amount. What is the total recommended daily amount of potassium?", "inst/gold_answer": 4250.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 114, "inst/question": "Mitzi received some gourmet brownies as a gift. The wrapper said each brownie was 480 calories, and had 240 calories of fat. What percent of the total calories in each brownie comes from fat?", "inst/gold_answer": 50.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 115, "inst/question": "The average price of a gallon of gas in one city in June 2014 was $3.71. The average price in that city in July was $3.64. Find the percent decrease.", "inst/gold_answer": 1.9, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 117, "inst/question": "Trong has 12% of each paycheck automatically deposited to his savings account. His last paycheck was $2165. How much money was deposited to Trong\u2019s savings account?", "inst/gold_answer": 259.8, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 118, "inst/question": "One serving of oatmeal has eight grams of fiber, which is 33% of the recommended daily amount. What is the total recommended daily amount of fiber, in grams?", "inst/gold_answer": 24.2, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 119, "inst/question": "A bacon cheeseburger at a popular fast food restaurant contains 2070 milligrams (mg) of sodium, which is 86% of the recommended daily amount. What is the total recommended daily amount of sodium, in milligrams?", "inst/gold_answer": 2407.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 120, "inst/question": "After 3 months on a diet, Lisa had lost 12% of her original weight. She lost 21 pounds. What was Lisa\u2019s original weight, in pounds?", "inst/gold_answer": 175.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 121, "inst/question": "Yuki bought a dress on sale for $72. The sale price was 60% of the original price. What was the original price of the dress?", "inst/gold_answer": 120.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 122, "inst/question": "Tim left a $9 tip for a $50 restaurant bill. What percent tip did he leave?", "inst/gold_answer": 18.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 123, "inst/question": "The nutrition fact sheet at a fast food restaurant says the fish sandwich has 380 calories, and 171 calories are from fat. What percent of the total calories is from fat?", "inst/gold_answer": 45.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 124, "inst/question": "Emma gets paid $3,000 per month. She pays $750 a month for rent. What percent of her monthly pay goes to rent?", "inst/gold_answer": 25.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 125, "inst/question": "Tamanika got a raise in her hourly pay, from $15.50 to $17.36. Find the percent increase.", "inst/gold_answer": 12.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 126, "inst/question": "Annual student fees at the University of California rose from about $4,000 in 2000 to about $12,000 in 2010. Find the percent increase.", "inst/gold_answer": 200.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 128, "inst/question": "Hernando\u2019s salary was $49,500 last year. This year his salary was cut to $44,055. Find the percent decrease.", "inst/gold_answer": 11.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 129, "inst/question": "At the campus coffee cart, a medium coffee costs $1.65. MaryAnne brings $2.00 with her when she buys a cup of coffee and leaves the change as a tip. What percent tip does she leave?", "inst/gold_answer": 21.2, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 130, "inst/question": "At a school concert, the total value of tickets sold was $1,506. Student tickets sold for $6 each and adult tickets sold for $9 each. The number of adult tickets sold was five less than three times the number of student tickets sold. How many student tickets were sold?", "inst/gold_answer": 47.0, "plan": "Method: System of linear equations"}
{"id": 131, "inst/question": "Galen sold 810 tickets for his church\u2019s carnival for a total of $2,820. Children\u2019s tickets cost $3 each and adult tickets cost $5 each. How many children\u2019s tickets did he sell?", "inst/gold_answer": 615.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 132, "inst/question": "Monica paid $8.36 for stamps. The number of 41-cent stamps was four more than twice the number of two-cent stamps. How many 41-cent stamps did Monica buy?", "inst/gold_answer": 20.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 133, "inst/question": "Henning is mixing raisins and nuts to make 10 pounds of trail mix. Raisins cost $2 a pound and nuts cost $6 a pound. If Henning wants his cost for the trail mix to be $5.20 a pound, how many pounds of raisins should he use?", "inst/gold_answer": 2.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 134, "inst/question": "The school play sold $550 in tickets one night. The number of $8 adult tickets was 10 less than twice the number of $5 child tickets. How many of adult tickets were sold?", "inst/gold_answer": 50.0, "plan": "Method: System of linear equations"}
{"id": 135, "inst/question": "The movie theater took in $1,220 one Monday night. The number of $7 child tickets was ten more than twice the number of $9 adult tickets. How many of child tickets were sold?", "inst/gold_answer": 110.0, "plan": "Method: System of linear equations"}
{"id": 136, "inst/question": "The ice rink sold 95 tickets for the afternoon skating session, for a total of $828. General admission tickets cost $10 each and youth tickets cost $8 each. How many general admission tickets were sold?", "inst/gold_answer": 34.0, "plan": "Method: System of linear equations"}
{"id": 137, "inst/question": "The box office sold 360 tickets to a concert at the college. The total receipts were $4170. General admission tickets cost $15 and student tickets cost $10. How many general admission tickets were sold?", "inst/gold_answer": 114.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 138, "inst/question": "Julie went to the post office and bought both $0.41 stamps and $0.26 postcards. She spent $51.40. The number of stamps was 20 more than twice the number of postcards. How many $0.41 stamps did she buy?", "inst/gold_answer": 100.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 139, "inst/question": "Maria spent $12.50 at the post office. She bought three times as many $0.41 stamps as $0.02 stamps. How many $0.41 stamps did she buy?", "inst/gold_answer": 30.0, "plan": "Method: System of linear equations"}
{"id": 140, "inst/question": "Hilda has $210 worth of $10 and $12 stock shares. The numbers of $10 shares is five more than twice the number of $12 shares. How many $10 shares does she have?", "inst/gold_answer": 15.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 141, "inst/question": "Lauren in making 15 liters of mimosas for a brunch banquet. Orange juice costs her $1.50 per liter and champagne costs her $12 per liter. How many liters of orange juice should she use for the mimosas to cost Lauren $5 per liter?", "inst/gold_answer": 10.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 142, "inst/question": "Kaapo is mixing Kona beans and Maui beans to make 25 pounds of coffee blend. Kona beans cost Kaapo $15 per pound and Maui beans cost $24 per pound. How many pounds of Kona beans should Kaapo use for his blend to cost him $17.70 per pound?", "inst/gold_answer": 17.5, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 143, "inst/question": "As the treasurer of her daughter\u2019s Girl Scout troop, Laney collected money for some girls and adults to go to a 3-day camp. Each girl paid $75 and each adult paid $30. The total amount of money collected for camp was $765. If the number of girls is three times the number of adults, how many girls paid for camp?", "inst/gold_answer": 9.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 144, "inst/question": "An express train and a local train leave Pittsburgh to travel to Washington, D.C. The express train can make the trip in 4 hours and the local train takes 5 hours for the trip. The speed of the express train is 12 miles per hour faster than the speed of the local train. Find the speed of the express train, in miles per hour.", "inst/gold_answer": 60.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 145, "inst/question": "Christopher and his parents live 115 miles apart. They met at a restaurant between their homes to celebrate his mother\u2019s birthday. Christopher drove 1.5 hours while his parents drove 1 hour to get to the restaurant. Christopher\u2019s average speed was 10 miles per hour faster than his parents\u2019 average speed. What were the average speed of Christopher as he drove to the restaurant, in miles per hour?", "inst/gold_answer": 50.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 146, "inst/question": "Two truck drivers leave a rest area on the interstate at the same time. One truck travels east and the other one travels west. The truck traveling west travels at 70 mph and the truck traveling east has an average speed of 60 mph. How many hours will they travel before they are 325 miles apart?", "inst/gold_answer": 2.5, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 147, "inst/question": "When Katie Mae walks to school, it takes her 30 minutes. If she rides her bike, it takes her 15 minutes. Her speed is three miles per hour faster when she rides her bike than when she walks. What is her walking speed, in miles per hour?", "inst/gold_answer": 3.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 148, "inst/question": "Lilah is moving from Portland to Seattle. It takes her three hours to go by train. Mason leaves the train station in Portland and drives to the train station in Seattle with all Lilah\u2019s boxes in his car. It takes him 2.4 hours to get to Seattle, driving at 15 miles per hour faster than the speed of the train. Find Mason\u2019s speed, in miles per hour.", "inst/gold_answer": 75.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 149, "inst/question": "Two busses go from Sacramento for San Diego. The express bus makes the trip in 6.8 hours and the local bus takes 10.2 hours for the trip. The speed of the express bus is 25 mph faster than the speed of the local bus. Find the speed of the express bus, in mph.", "inst/gold_answer": 75.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 150, "inst/question": "Saul drove his truck 3 hours from Dallas towards Kansas City and stopped at a truck stop to get dinner. At the truck stop he met Erwin, who had driven 4 hours from Kansas City towards Dallas. The distance between Dallas and Kansas City is 542 miles, and Erwin\u2019s speed was eight miles per hour slower than Saul\u2019s speed. Find the speed of Saul, in mph.", "inst/gold_answer": 82.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 151, "inst/question": "Sisters Helen and Anne live 332 miles apart. For Thanksgiving, they met at their other sister\u2019s house partway between their homes. Helen drove 3.2 hours and Anne drove 2.8 hours. Helen\u2019s average speed was four miles per hour faster than Anne\u2019s. Find Helen\u2019s average speed, in miles per hour.", "inst/gold_answer": 57.2, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 152, "inst/question": "Elvira and Aletheia live 3.1 miles apart on the same street. They are in a study group that meets at a coffee shop between their houses. It took Elvira half an hour and Aletheia two-thirds of an hour to walk to the coffee shop. Aletheia\u2019s speed is 0.6 miles per hour slower than Elvira\u2019s speed. Find Elvira\u2019s walking speed, in miles per hour.", "inst/gold_answer": 3.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 155, "inst/question": "Lorena walks the path around the park in 30 minutes. If she jogs, it takes her 20 minutes. Her jogging speed is 1.5 miles per hour faster than her walking speed. Find Lorena\u2019s walking speed, in miles per hour.", "inst/gold_answer": 3.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 156, "inst/question": "Cassius drives his boat upstream for 45 minutes. It takes him 30 minutes to return downstream. His speed going upstream is three miles per hour slower than his speed going downstream. Find his upstream speed, in miles per hour.", "inst/gold_answer": 6.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 157, "inst/question": "Three-fourths of the people at a concert are children. If there are 87 children, what is the total number of people at the concert?", "inst/gold_answer": 116.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 158, "inst/question": "The sum of a number and three is forty-one. Find the number.", "inst/gold_answer": 38.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 160, "inst/question": "12.5% of what number is 20?", "inst/gold_answer": 160.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 163, "inst/question": "Dolores bought a crib on sale for $350. The sale price was 40% of the original price. What was the original price of the crib?", "inst/gold_answer": 875.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 164, "inst/question": "Angel\u2019s got a raise in his annual salary from $55,400 to $56,785. Find the percent increase.", "inst/gold_answer": 2.5, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 165, "inst/question": "Paulette has $140 in $5 and $10 bills. The number of $10 bills is one less than twice the number of $5 bills. How many $5 bills does she have?", "inst/gold_answer": 6.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 166, "inst/question": "A church luncheon made $842. Adult tickets cost $10 each and children\u2019s tickets cost $6 each. The number of children was 12 more than twice the number of adults. How many adult tickets were sold?", "inst/gold_answer": 35.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 167, "inst/question": "125 tickets were sold for the jazz band concert for a total of $1,022. Student tickets cost $6 each and general admission tickets cost $10 each. How many student tickets were sold?", "inst/gold_answer": 57.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 168, "inst/question": "Ana spent $4.06 buying stamps. The number of $0.41 stamps she bought was five more than the number of $0.26 stamps. How many $0.41 stamps did she buy?", "inst/gold_answer": 8.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 169, "inst/question": "Marquese is making 10 pounds of trail mix from raisins and nuts. Raisins cost $3.45 per pound and nuts cost $7.95 per pound. How many pounds of raisins should Marquese use for the trail mix to cost him $6.96 per pound?", "inst/gold_answer": 2.2, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 170, "inst/question": "When Gabe drives from Sacramento to Redding it takes him 2.2 hours. It takes Elsa 2 hours to drive the same distance. Elsa\u2019s speed is seven miles per hour faster than Gabe\u2019s speed. Find Gabe\u2019s speed, in miles per hour.", "inst/gold_answer": 70.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 172, "inst/question": "Sondra is making 10 quarts of punch from fruit juice and club soda. The number of quarts of fruit juice is 4 times the number of quarts of club soda. How many quarts of fruit juice does Sondra need?", "inst/gold_answer": 8.0, "plan": "Method: System of linear equations"}
{"id": 173, "inst/question": "Molly is making strawberry infused water. For each ounce of strawberry juice, she uses three times as many ounces of water. How many ounces of strawberry juice does she need to make 64 ounces of strawberry infused water?", "inst/gold_answer": 16.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 174, "inst/question": "Enrique is making a party mix that contains raisins and nuts. For each ounce of nuts, he uses twice the amount of raisins. How many ounces of nuts does he need to make 24 ounces of party mix?", "inst/gold_answer": 8.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 175, "inst/question": "Leo is planning his spring flower garden. He wants to plant tulip and daffodil bulbs. He will plant 6 times as many daffodil bulbs as tulip bulbs. If he wants to plant 350 bulbs, how many tulip bulbs should he plant?", "inst/gold_answer": 50.0, "plan": "Method: System of linear equations"}
{"id": 176, "inst/question": "The perimeter of a rectangle is 88. The length is five more than twice the width. Find the length.", "inst/gold_answer": 31.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 177, "inst/question": "Heather has been offered two options for her salary as a trainer at the gym. Option A would pay her $25,000 plus $15 for each training session. Option B would pay her $10,000 + $40 for each training session. How many training sessions would make the salary options equal?", "inst/gold_answer": 600.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 178, "inst/question": "The perimeter of a rectangle is 84. The length is 10 more than three times the width. Find the length.", "inst/gold_answer": 34.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 179, "inst/question": "Jackie has been offered positions by two cable companies. The first company pays a salary of $ 14,000 plus a commission of $100 for each cable package sold. The second pays a salary of $20,000 plus a commission of $25 for each cable package sold. How many cable packages would need to be sold to make the total pay the same?", "inst/gold_answer": 80.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 180, "inst/question": "Mitchell currently sells stoves for company A at a salary of $12,000 plus a $150 commission for each stove he sells. Company B offers him a position with a salary of $24,000 plus a $50 commission for each stove he sells. How many stoves would Mitchell need to sell for the options to be equal?", "inst/gold_answer": 120.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 181, "inst/question": "Joe stops at a burger restaurant every day on his way to work. Monday he had one order of medium fries and two small sodas, which had a total of 620 calories. Tuesday he had two orders of medium fries and one small soda, for a total of 820 calories. How many calories are there in one order of medium fries?", "inst/gold_answer": 340.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 182, "inst/question": "Andrea is buying some new shirts and sweaters. She is able to buy 3 shirts and 2 sweaters for $114 or she is able to buy 2 shirts and 4 sweaters for $164. How much does a shirt cost?", "inst/gold_answer": 16.0, "plan": "Method: System of linear equations"}
{"id": 183, "inst/question": "The total amount of sodium in 2 hot dogs and 3 cups of cottage cheese is 4720 mg. The total amount of sodium in 5 hot dogs and 2 cups of cottage cheese is 6300 mg. How much sodium is in a hot dog, in mg?", "inst/gold_answer": 860.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 184, "inst/question": "Devon is 26 years older than his son Cooper. The sum of their ages is 50. Find Devon's age.", "inst/gold_answer": 38.0, "plan": "Method: System of linear equations"}
{"id": 185, "inst/question": "When Jenna spent 10 minutes on the elliptical trainer and then did circuit training for 20 minutes, her fitness app says she burned 278 calories. When she spent 20 minutes on the elliptical trainer and 30 minutes circuit training she burned 473 calories. How many calories does she burn for each minute on the elliptical trainer?", "inst/gold_answer": 11.2, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 186, "inst/question": "Joni left St. Louis on the interstate, driving west towards Denver at a speed of 65 miles per hour. Half an hour later, Kelly left St. Louis on the same route as Joni, driving 78 miles per hour. How many hours will it take Kelly to catch up to Joni?", "inst/gold_answer": 2.5, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 187, "inst/question": "A river cruise ship sailed 60 miles downstream for 4 hours and then took 5 hours sailing upstream to return to the dock. Find the speed of the ship in still water, in miles per hour.", "inst/gold_answer": 13.5, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 188, "inst/question": "A private jet can fly 1095 miles in three hours with a tailwind but only 987 miles in three hours into a headwind. Find the speed of the jet in still air, in miles per hour.", "inst/gold_answer": 347.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 189, "inst/question": "A married couple together earn $75,000. The husband earns $15,000 more than five times what his wife earns. What does the wife earn?", "inst/gold_answer": 10000.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 190, "inst/question": "Daniela invested a total of $50,000, some in a certificate of deposit (CD) and the remainder in bonds. The amount invested in bonds was $5000 more than twice the amount she put into the CD. How much did she invest in the CD?", "inst/gold_answer": 15000.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 191, "inst/question": "In her last two years in college, Marlene received $42,000 in loans. The first year she received a loan that was $6,000 less than three times the amount of the second year\u2019s loan. What was the amount of her loan for the first year?", "inst/gold_answer": 30000.0, "plan": "Method: System of linear equations"}
{"id": 192, "inst/question": "Alyssa is twelve years older than her sister, Bethany. The sum of their ages is forty-four. Find Alyssa's age.", "inst/gold_answer": 28.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 193, "inst/question": "The age of Noelle\u2019s dad is six less than three times Noelle\u2019s age. The sum of their ages is seventy-four. Find Noelle\u2019s dad's age.", "inst/gold_answer": 54.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 194, "inst/question": "Two containers of gasoline hold a total of fifty gallons. The big container can hold ten gallons less than twice the small container. How many gallons does the big container hold?", "inst/gold_answer": 30.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 195, "inst/question": "Shelly spent 10 minutes jogging and 20 minutes cycling and burned 300 calories. The next day, Shelly swapped times, doing 20 minutes of jogging and 10 minutes of cycling and burned the same number of calories. How many calories were burned for each minute of jogging?", "inst/gold_answer": 10.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 196, "inst/question": "Troy and Lisa were shopping for school supplies. Each purchased different quantities of the same notebook and thumb drive. Troy bought four notebooks and five thumb drives for $116. Lisa bought two notebooks and three thumb dives for $68. Find the cost of each notebook.", "inst/gold_answer": 4.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 197, "inst/question": "Sarah left Minneapolis heading east on the interstate at a speed of 60 mph. Her sister followed her on the same route, leaving two hours later and driving at a rate of 70 mph. How many hours will it take for Sarah\u2019s sister to catch up to Sarah?", "inst/gold_answer": 12.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 198, "inst/question": "At the end of spring break, Lucy left the beach and drove back towards home, driving at a rate of 40 mph. Lucy\u2019s friend left the beach for home 30 minutes (half an hour) later, and drove 50 mph. How many hours did it take Lucy\u2019s friend to catch up to Lucy?", "inst/gold_answer": 2.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 199, "inst/question": "The Jones family took a 12 mile canoe ride down the Indian River in two hours. After lunch, the return trip back up the river took three hours. Find the rate of the canoe in still water, in miles per hour.", "inst/gold_answer": 5.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 200, "inst/question": "A motor boat traveled 18 miles down a river in two hours but going back upstream, it took 4.5 hours due to the current. Find the rate of the motor boat in still water, in miles per hour.", "inst/gold_answer": 6.5, "plan": "Method: System of linear equations"}
{"id": 201, "inst/question": "A small jet can fly 1,072 miles in 4 hours with a tailwind but only 848 miles in 4 hours into a headwind. Find the speed of the jet in still air, in miles per hour.", "inst/gold_answer": 240.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 202, "inst/question": "A commercial jet can fly 868 miles in 2 hours with a tailwind but only 792 miles in 2 hours into a headwind. Find the speed of the jet in still air, in miles per hour.", "inst/gold_answer": 415.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 203, "inst/question": "The box office at a movie theater sold 147 tickets for the evening show, and receipts totaled $1,302. A child ticket costs $8, and an adult ticket costs $11. How many $11 adult tickets were sold?", "inst/gold_answer": 42.0, "plan": "Method: System of linear equations"}
{"id": 204, "inst/question": "Carson wants to make 20 pounds of trail mix using nuts and chocolate chips. His budget requires that the trail mix costs him $7.60 per pound. Nuts cost $9.00 per pound and chocolate chips cost $2.00 per pound. How many pounds of nuts should he use?", "inst/gold_answer": 16.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 205, "inst/question": "Tickets to a Broadway show cost $35 for adults and $15 for children. The total receipts for 1650 tickets at one performance were $47,150. How many adult tickets were sold?", "inst/gold_answer": 1120.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 206, "inst/question": "Tickets for a train cost $10 for children and $22 for adults. Josie paid $1,200 for a total of 72 tickets. How many children\u2019s tickets did Josie buy?", "inst/gold_answer": 32.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 207, "inst/question": "Tickets for a dance recital cost $15 for adults and $7 for children. The dance company sold 253 tickets and the total receipts were $2,771. How many adult tickets were sold?", "inst/gold_answer": 125.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 208, "inst/question": "A cashier has 30 bills, all of which are $10 or $20 bills. The total value of the money is $460. How many of the  $10 bill does the cashier have?", "inst/gold_answer": 14.0, "plan": "Method: System of linear equations"}
{"id": 209, "inst/question": "Hannah has to make twenty-five gallons of punch for a potluck. The punch is made of soda and fruit drink. The cost of the soda is $1.79 per gallon and the cost of the fruit drink is $2.49 per gallon. Hannah\u2019s budget requires that the punch cost $2.21 per gallon. How many gallons of soda does she need?", "inst/gold_answer": 10.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 210, "inst/question": "Julia and her husband own a coffee shop. They experimented with mixing a City Roast Columbian coffee that cost $7.80 per pound with French Roast Columbian coffee that cost $8.10 per pound to make a 20 pound blend. Their blend should cost them $7.92 per pound. How much of City Roast Columbian coffee should they buy?", "inst/gold_answer": 12.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 211, "inst/question": "Jotham needs 70 liters of a 50% alcohol solution. He has a 30% and an 80% solution available. How many liters of the 30% solution should he mix to make the 50% solution?", "inst/gold_answer": 42.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 212, "inst/question": "A scientist needs 65 liters of a 15% alcohol solution. She has available a 25% and a 12% solution. How many liters of the 25% solution should she mix to make the 15% solution?", "inst/gold_answer": 15.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 213, "inst/question": "A 40% antifreeze solution is to be mixed with a 70% antifreeze solution to get 240 liters of a 50% solution. How many liters of the 40% solution will be used?", "inst/gold_answer": 160.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 214, "inst/question": "Laurie was completing the treasurer\u2019s report for her son\u2019s Boy Scout troop at the end of the school year. She didn\u2019t remember how many boys had paid the $15 full-year registration fee and how many had paid the $10 partial-year fee. She knew that the number of boys who paid for a full-year was ten more than the number who paid for a partial-year. If $250 was collected for all the registrations, how many boys had paid the full-year fee?", "inst/gold_answer": 14.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 215, "inst/question": "LaVelle is making a pitcher of caffe mocha. For each ounce of chocolate syrup, she uses five ounces of coffee. How many ounces of chocolate syrup does she need to make 48 ounces of caffe mocha?", "inst/gold_answer": 8.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 216, "inst/question": "Last month Jim and Debbie earned $7,200. Debbie earned $1,600 more than Jim earned. How much did Debbie earn?", "inst/gold_answer": 4400.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 217, "inst/question": "Pam is 3 years older than her sister, Jan. The sum of their ages is 99. Find Pam's age.", "inst/gold_answer": 51.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 218, "inst/question": "Sheila and Lenore were driving to their grandmother\u2019s house. Lenore left one hour after Sheila. Sheila drove at a rate of 45 mph, and Lenore drove at a rate of 60 mph. How many hours will it take for Lenore to catch up to Sheila?", "inst/gold_answer": 3.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 219, "inst/question": "Marcus can drive his boat 36 miles down the river in three hours but takes four hours to return upstream. Find the rate of the boat in still water, in miles per hour.", "inst/gold_answer": 10.5, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 220, "inst/question": "Lynn paid a total of $2,780 for 261 tickets to the theater. Student tickets cost $10 and adult tickets cost $15. How many student tickets did Lynn buy?", "inst/gold_answer": 227.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
{"id": 221, "inst/question": "Yumi wants to make 12 cups of party mix using candies and nuts. Her budget requires the party mix to cost her $1.29 per cup. The candies are $2.49 per cup and the nuts are $0.69 per cup. How many cups of candies should she use?", "inst/gold_answer": 4.0, "plan": "System of linear equations"}
